Guide to the Building Trades Oral History Project OH.045
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Building Trades Oral History Project
1998-2002
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
OH.045
3.5 Linear Feet
Conditions Governing Access
Unless otherwise noted, materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Interviews conducted by Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives staff between 1998 and 2001. The accession numbers associated with this collection are 1950.094 and 1978.015.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
The digital access copies in the collection were created by the Barbara Goldsmith Preservation and Conservation Department. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact nyuspecialcollections@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
- Transcripts, cuid14499 (Box 1)
- Adam, Eleanor, Jun 01, 2000; cuid14537 (Box 2, Cassette 5A, 5B, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14537A, cuid14537B)
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 63 min.[A] and 36 min.[B]
- Allen, Kenneth (Metalic Lathers Union, Local 46), Dec 27, 2001; cuid14452 (Box 5, Cassette 28, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14452)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 72 minutes
- Alongi, Vincent (Carpenters and Joiners, Local 2090), Oct 24, 2000; cuid14453 (Box 5, Cassette 34A, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14453A)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 94 minutes
- Andrucki, George (Sheetmetal Workers, Local 28), Dec 2, 1998; cuid14454 (Box 5, Cassette 33A, 33B, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14454A, cuid14454B)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 72 minutes [A] and 94 minutes [B]
- Bartels, Robert (Steamfitters Local 638), Dec 18, 2001; cuid14455 (Box 5, Cassette 32A, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14455A)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 84 min.
- Blain, William (International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 3), Apr 15, 1998; cuid14456 (Box 5, Cassette 31A, 31B, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14456A, cuid14456B)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 63 min. [A] and 56 min. [B]
- Bloom, April, Jul 11, 2000; cuid14538 (Box 2, Cassette 1A, 1B, Box Digitized Access Files, Cassette cuid14538A, cuid14538B)
- Bombardiere, Mio (Sheetmetal Workers, Local 137), Nov 18, 1999; cuid14457 (Box 5, Cassette 30A, 30B, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14457A, cuid14457B)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 95 min. [A] and 8 min. [B], Note: Side 2 of tape B is blank.
- Brennan, Vincent (Steamfitters, Local 638), May 21, 1998; cuid14458 (Box 5, Cassette 27A, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14458A)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 85 min. [A]
- Colbert, Neil (Tile, Marble and Terrazo, Local 7), Jun 10, 1999; cuid14459 (Box 2, Cassette cuid14459, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14459)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 78 min.
- Coletti, Louis J. (Building Trades Employers Association), Jul 31, 2001; cuid14460 (Box 2, Cassette 29A, 29B, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14460A, cuid14460B)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 94 min. [A] and 28 min. [B], Note: Side 2 of tape B is blank.
- Collins, Paul (Sheetmetal Workers, Local 137), Oct 4, 1999; cuid14461 (Box 2, Cassette 26A, 26B, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14461A, cuid14461B)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 94 min. [A] and 61 min. [B]
- Contello, Sal (Bricklayers, Local 1), Jun 12, 1998; cuid14462 (Box 2, Cassette 25A, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14462A)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 40 min.
- Cush, Edward (Ironworkers, Local 361), Mar 21, 2001; cuid14463; 2 audiocassette Part 1 and 2 of the same interview (Box 2, Cassette 24A, 24B, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14463A, cuid14463B)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 94 min. [A] and 67 min. [B]
- Daly, Martin (Carpenters District Council), Oct 29, 1998; cuid14464 (Box 2, Cassette 23A, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14464)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 47 min., Note: Side 2 is blank
- Doyle, Jack (Ironworkers, Local 40), Jan 15, 2002; cuid14465; 2 audiocassette Part 1 and Part 2 of the same interview. (Box 2, Cassette 6A, 6B, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14465A, cuid14465B)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Durations: 94 min. [A] and 40 min. [B]
- Forde, Michael (Carpenters District Council), Mar 20, 2002; cuid14466 (Box 2, Cassette 22A, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14466A)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 82 min.
- Gerosa, Al (Cement League of Greater New York), Oct 1, 2001; cuid14467 (Box 2, Cassette 21A, 21B, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14467A, cuid14467B)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 64 min. [A] and 60 min. [B]
- Glynn, Eugene (Steamfitters, Local 638), May 22, 1998; cuid14468 (Box 2, Cassette 19A, 19B, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14468A, cuid14468B)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 94 min. [A] and 30 min. [B]
- Hill, Charlie (Tile, Marble and Terrazzo, Local 7), May 11, 1999; cuid14469 (Box 2, Cassette 20A, 20B, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14469A, cuid14469B)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 25 min. [A] and 95 min. [B]
- Hirsch, Sam (Painters District Council), May 7, 2001; cuid14470 (Box 2, Cassette 17A, 17B, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14470A, cuid14470B)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 94 min. [A] and 63 min.[B]
- Hirsch, Sam (Painters District Council), Jun 07, 2001; cuid14540 (Box 2, Cassette 18B, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14540B)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 94 min.[B], Note: Tape A is missing.
- Holloway, Dennis (International Masonry Institute of Bricklayers and Allied Trades), Jun 25, 1998; cuid14471 (Box 2, Cassette 16A, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14471)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 62 min.
- Humphrey, Thomas (Stone Derrickmen and Riggers, Local 197), Oct 12, 1999; cuid14472 (Box 2, Cassette 15A, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14472)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 93 min.
- Kelly, John (Iron Workers, Local 40), Nov 14, 2001; cuid14473; 2 audiocassette Part 1 and 2 of the same interview (Box 3, Cassette 12A, 12B, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14473A, cuid14473B)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassettes, Duration: 57 min. [A] and 87 min. [B]
- Kelly, William (Iron Workers, Local 197), Nov 12, 1999; cuid14474 (Box 3, Cassette 11A, 11B, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14474A, cuid14474B)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 63 min. [A] and 57 min. [B]
- Kennedy, John (Building and Construction Trades Council of Nassau and Suffolk Counties), Oct 31, 2001; cuid14475 (Box 3, Cassette 10A, 10B, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14475A, cuid14475B)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 63 min.[A] and 37 min.[B]
- Lanzafame, Santo (Bricklayers, Local 1), Nov 18, 1998; cuid14476 (Box 6, Cassette 39A, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14476)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 50 min.
- Ledwith, Robert (Metallic Lathers, Local 46), Mar 19, 2001; cuid14477 (Box 3, Cassette 8A, 8B, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14477A, cuid14477B)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 21 min. [A] and 94 min. [B], Note: Sound quality is poor.
- Ledwith, Robert (Metallic Lathers, Local 46), Dec 28, 2001; cuid14478 (Box 3, Cassette 9A, 9B, 9C, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14478A, cuid14478B, cuid14478C)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 63 min.[A], 62 min.[B] and 20 min.[C]
- Levine, Louis (Former Deputy Commissioner of Labor), Jan 20, 1999; cuid14479 (Box 3, Cassette 7A,7B, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14479A, cuid14479B)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 94 min.[A] and 12 min.[B]
- Lusardi, Dennis (Ironworkers, Local 580), Dec 28, 2001; cuid14480; 1 audiocassette (Box 3, Cassette 46A, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14480)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 92 min.
- Maiello, Gene (New York District of Carpenters), Nov 27, 2000; cuid14481 (Box 3, Cassette 13A, 13B, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14481A, cuid14481B)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 63 min.[A] and 19 min.[B]
- Malloy, Edward (Building and Construction Trades Council), Aug 8, 2002; cuid14482 (Box 2, Cassette 4A, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14482)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 81 min.
- Martin, Raymond (General Society of Mechanics and Tradesmen), Jul 31, 2002; cuid14483 (Box 2, Cassette 2A, 2B, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14483A)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 81 min.[A]. Note: Tape B was not transferred.
- McGuire, Ray (Contractors Association of Greater New York), Nov 12, 2001; cuid14484 (Box 6, Cassette 38A, 38B, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14484A, cuid14484B)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 94 min.[A] and 28 min.[B]
- Nicastri, Ronald (Tile, Marble and Terrazzo, Local 7), Jun 21, 1999; cuid14485 (Box 6, Cassette 37A, 37B, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14485A, cuid14485B)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 94 min.[A] and 41 min. [B]
- O'Brien, William (Painters District Council 9), Nov 13, 2001; cuid14486 (Box 5, Cassette 36A, 36B, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14486A, cuid14486B)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 63 min.[A] and 56 min.[B]
- O'Donnell, John (Association of Plumbing Contractors), Oct 26, 2001; cuid14487 (Box 3, Cassette 14A, 14B, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14487A, cuid14487B)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 94 min.[A], 12 min.[B]
- O'Kane, Richard (Ironworkers, Local 361), Mar 9, 2001; cuid14488; 2 audiocassette Part 1 and 2 of the same interview (Box 6, Cassette 45A, 45B, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14488A, cuid14488B)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 94 min. [A], 9 min [B]. Note: Volume fluctuates between interviewer and interviewee.
- Robinson, Guy, Aug 09, 2002; cuid14539 (Box 2, Cassette 3A, 3B, Box Digitized Access Files, Cassette cuid14539A)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 74 min.[A], Note: Tape B is a duplicate of tape A.
- Rothberg, William (Sheet Metal Industry Promotion Fund), Nov 20, 2000; cuid14489 (Box 6, Cassette 44A, 44B, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14489A, cuid14489B)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 94 min.[A] and 19 min.[B]
- Rothberg, William (Sheet Metal Industry Promotion Fund), Oct 19, 2000; cuid14490 (Box 6, Cassette 43A, 43B, Box Digitized Access Files, Cassette cuid14490A, cuid14490B)
  Formation: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 63 min.[A] and 11 min.[B]
- Simmons, Alan (Ironworkers District Council), Jan 19, 2001; cuid14491 (Box 6, Cassette 42A, 42B, Box Digitized Access Files, Cassette cuid14491A, cuid14492B)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 94 min.[A] and 5 min.[B]
- Thomassen, Peter (Dockbuilders, Local 1456), Nov 30, 1998; cuid14492 (Box 3, Cassette 41A, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14492A)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 70 min.
- Torpey, John R. (Steamfitters, Local 638), Jan 12, 1999; cuid14493 (Box 3, Cassette 40A 40B, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14493A, cuid14493B)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 94 min.[A] and 14 min.[B]
- Ulrich, Werner (Steamfitters, Local 638), May 6, 1998; cuid14494 (Box 4, Cassette 48A, 48B, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14494A, cuid14494B)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 63 min.[A] and 63 min.[B]
- Valegatos, Sandy (Painters District Council 9), Jan 10, 2001; cuid14495 (Box 4, Cassette 47A, 47B, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14495A, cuid14495B)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 63 min.[A] and 29 min. [B]
- Walsh, Edward J. (Ironworkers, Local 40), Jan 5, 2001; cuid14496; 3 audiocassette Parts 1, 2, and 3 of the same interview (Box 4, Cassette 49A, 49B, 49C, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14496A, cuid14496B, cuid14496C)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Durations: 63 min. [A], 63 min. [B], 10 min. [C]
- Walsh, Robert (Ironworkers, Local 40), Aug 24, 2001; cuid14497; 2 audiocassette Duplicates. One tape is the master, and the other is a high speed dub. (Box 4, Cassette 50A, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14497)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 116 min.
- Winbush, Zacharius (Bricklayers, Local 1), Jun 12, 1998; cuid14498 (Box 4, Cassette 451A, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid14498A)
  Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 46 min.
- Access Audio CDs (Box Shared Tamiment 123)